Guide to the Center for the Study of Human Rights Records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Center for the Study of Human Rights Records,
1981-2004
[Bulk dates: 1987-2001]
Center for the Study of Human Rights.
11.5 linear feet (25 document boxes, one index card box)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY. 10027
HR#0005
6460813
This collection contains materials generated and collected by the Center for the Study of Human Rights, a research and training center at Columbia University.
Historical Note
Founded at Columbia University in 1978, the Center for the Study of Human Rights is one of the oldest university human rights programs in the United States. The Center advances the understanding of human rights issues through its goals of "providing excellent human rights education to Columbia students, fostering innovative interdisciplinary academic research, and offering its expertise in capacity building to human rights leaders, organizations, and universities around the world."
The Center plays a supporting role in human rights instruction at Columbia; it does not oversee or evaluate programs, but helps facilitate communication between interested students and faculty members from several departments. The Center posts lists of courses with a human rights focus, helps find adjunct faculty to teach specific topics, and coordinates interdisciplinary events, such as a colloquium for dissertation students. The overall goal is to make human rights education an integral part of many fields of study, rather than a separate component.
Research carried out by CSHR has taken many forms over the years. Initially, CHSR focused on projects that would encourage constitutionalism as a basis of government. In the early 1990s, for example, the Center created Constitutionalism and Rights: Project on China, which brought Chinese and Western scholars together to research and discuss constitutional questions. CSHR also supported the Cambodian Genocide Documentation Project (1983-1987), created in collaboration with David Hawk, which documented destruction in Cambodia under the Khmer Rouge through taped oral histories and reports, and the Project on Children and War (1988-1992) which provided research and analysis to back other organizations fighting for policies and programs for children in war zones. More recently, the Center has been committed to research that helps developing countries create effective local institutions, such as judiciary bodies and human rights organizations, which can make a democratic system run more smoothly.
The Center's capacity building programs are intended to provide training and skills to human rights leaders and researchers, especially those who have difficulty acquiring them in their own countries. CSHR's ongoing Human Rights Advocates Program brings twelve such individuals from countries in the Global South to Columbia University each year. Advocates participate in courses and training workshops on topics such as networking, fundraising, and law, attend brown bag seminars, and meet with human rights leaders in New York and Washington, DC. The program has met with considerable success; participants frequently express their gratitude for the new abilities and knowledge they take back to their organizations.
The Center has completed many shorter programs, including the Uganda Visitors Project (1990) and the Liberia Project (1993-1996) which bring training people that need it. Between 1995 and 1999 the Center conducted the Religion, Human Rights, and Religious Freedom Program, which aimed to "promote interaction between religious communities and the international human rights movement, as well as to enhance concern for religious freedom and religious tolerance." Funded by the Pew Charitable Trusts and generally referred to as the Pew Program, it provided training for scholars from Central and Eastern Europe and the former Soviet Union. The seven-month fellowship was divided into two parts; for the first four months, fellows studied at Columbia and attended seminars and workshops on human rights issues. Following this, each fellow completed a three-month internship with a human rights organization that specialized in religious freedom and tolerance. The program also featured an annual conference on religious issues in Eastern Europe.
The Center also managed the Belldegrun Human Rights Research and Training Fellowship from 1998 until 2001. It allowed one advocate from Denmark, Finland, Norway, or Sweden to attend Columbia for a year. Fellows studied alongside members of HRAP and other programs while outlining a course schedule and research project in an area of international human rights.
Scope and Content
Although the collection documents a number of the Center's activities, the bulk of the material relates to its training and capacity building programs. The Human Rights Advocacy Program (HRAP) and the Religion, Human Rights, and Religious Freedom Program (Pew Program) are most thoroughly represented, but smaller amounts of material exist for the Belldegrun Fellowship, the Human Rights Colloquium (HRC), and others. Correspondence, project goal descriptions, admission criteria, schedules, evaluations, and reports show how these programs operated and changed.
The collection also contains administrative documents such as meeting minutes and annual reports; brochures and notes from workshops and conferences; general information on other NGOs; and materials such as course lists, course descriptions, syllabi, and long-term plans that demonstrate the Center's role in human rights instruction at Columbia.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into four series.
Series I: Administrative Files, 1988-2001
Series II: Human Rights Instruction, 1981-2002
Series III: Training and Capacity Building, 1987-2004
Series IV: Conferences, Workshops, and Roundtables, 1995-2003
Subjects
Columbia University.; Developing countries.; Education.; Human rights.; Human rights--study and teaching.; Human rights workers.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
CSHR Deposit 2006 accn number
- Series I: Administrative Files, 1988-2001.
  - General/background Information, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence
    - Prudential Fellowship Program at Columbia, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Peace Education Program, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Khmer Translation, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Steve Marks--Visit to Cambodia, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Electronic Records, 1994-1999 (3.5" floppy disks) (66 disks) (Box 26)
  - Fundraising
    - Grants, 1993, 1998, (2 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 7 to 8)
    - Bradesco Foundation Visit, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Goals, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Meeting Minutes and Notes
    - Director's Meetings, 1995-1996, (6 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Executive Board Meetings, 1996-1999, (9 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 17 to 25)
    - Staff Meetings, 1995-1998, (3 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 1 to 3)
  - Website Project, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - NGO/Organization Files
    - NGO Bibliography, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - America's Development Foundation, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - American Jewish Committee, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - American Jewish World Service, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Amnesty International, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Asia Foundation, 1996-2000, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 10 to 11)
    - Aspen Institute, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Association Internationale pour la Defense de la Liberte Religieuse, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Ayrton Senna Institute, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Baha'i International Community, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Balkan Institute, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Belgrade Center for Human Rights, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Bellevue/NYU Program for Survivors of Torture, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Birmingham University Human Rights Law and Practice Programme, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Board of British Jews, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Calamus Foundation, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Carnegie Council, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Center for International Health and Cooperation, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Center for Religious Pluralism, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Center for Women's Global Leadership, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Christian Peacemaker Teams, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Christian Solidarity International, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Church Avenue Merchants Block Association (CAMBA), 1994 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Civil Society Forum of the Americas, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Coalition for Immigrant Rights, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Columbia University Conflict Resolution Program, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Columbia University Law School Center for Public Interest Law, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Columbia University Law School Public Interest Law Initiative in Transitional Societies, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Columbia University School of Public Health: Program for the Study of Sexuality, Gender, Health, and Human Rights, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Corresponding Academy on Civil Society, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Doctors of the World, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - The Doe Fund, Inc: Ready, Willing, and Able Program, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Emory University, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Evangelische Gesellschaft Stuttgart, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Ford Foundation--Non-Grant Correspondence, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Fordham Law School Joseph R. Crowley Human Rights Program, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Forefront, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Foundation for a Civil Society, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Friedrich Ebert Foundation, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Fund for Peace, 1994-1997, (2 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 20 to 21)
    - Gay Men of African Descent (GMAD), 1997 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Glenmary Research Institute, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Global Kids, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Globalvisions, Inc., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - The Harriman Institute, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Helsinki Foundation for Human Rights, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - High Commission for Human Rights, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Human Rights Advocates International, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Human Rights Watch, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Human Rights without Borders, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Indonesia Society, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Institute for East West Studies, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Institute of International Education, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Institute of Jewish Affairs, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - International Center for Migration, Ethnicity and Citizenship, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - International Gay and Lesbian Human Rights Commission, 1996-1999 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - International Helsinki Federation for Human Rights, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - International NGO Center on Human Rights, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - International Jewish Women's Human Right Watch, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - International Religious Freedom Project, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Interreligious Coordinating Council, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Israel Interfaith Association, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Israel Religious Action Center, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - John Jay College of Criminal Justice, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Keston Institute, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Law and Liberty Trust, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Lawyers Committee for Human Rights, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Luce Foundation, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Magnus Hirschfeld Center for Human Rights, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Media Development Loan Fund, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Middle East Council of Churches, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Moscow Human Rights Research Center, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - NAFSA, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - National Civic Education Program, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - National Conference on Soviet Jewery, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Network of East-West Women, 1996, (2 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 20 to 21)
    - Niwano Peace Fund, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - NYC NGO list, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Oxfam America, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Parliamentarians for Global Action, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Project on Religion and Human Rights, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Public Interest Law Initiative, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Rights Link Project, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Rights and Wrongs, 1997-1999 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Rikers Island Correction Department, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Roosevelt Institute, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Rutherford Institute, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - St. Andrews Biblical Theological College, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Scholars at Risk, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - UNICEF, 1996-1999 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Union of Councils, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - United Nations, 1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Vera Institute of Justice, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - The Willberforce Council, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Women's Campaign for Soviet Jewry, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Women's Environment and Development Organization, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Series II: Human Rights Instruction, 1981-2002.
  - Subseries II.1: Columbia Human Rights Curriculum, 1981-2002
    - Certificate in Human Rights--General, 1987-1990 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Course Lists
      - Human Rights Courses, 1981-1991 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Race Relations Courses, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Curriculum Review, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Human Rights Syllabi, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - GSAS Syllabi, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Interdepartmental Committee on Human Rights, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Human Rights Research and Development Plan, 1992-1996 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Evaluation of HR Program, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Research--Assuring Children's Rights in Conflict and Post Conflict Situations, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Syllabi and Course Requirements (by course title)
      - Colloquium on Conceptual and Theoretical Issues, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Colloquium on International Human Rights, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - Constitutionalism in Eastern Europe, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Constitutional Law, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - The Growth of Individual Rights: Ideas and Politics, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Human Rights and the Democratic Transition in Latin America, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Human Rights in Eastern Europe, 1987-1997 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Human Rights and Economic Development, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Human Rights and International Affairs, 1988-1996 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Human Rights and International Law, 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Human Rights, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Human Rights in the International System, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Human Rights and Foreign Policy, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Human Rights in the Middle East, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Human and Social Dimensions of Peace: Human Rights Education, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - The Individual and the Middle East, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - International Business and International Human Rights, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - International Human Rights, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - International Law, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - International Protection of Human Rights, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Latin American Law, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Refugees, Migrations, and Human Rights, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Rethinking Human Rights, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Seminar on Human Rights and Foreign Policy, 1987-1989 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Social Security, Individual Rights, and Social Policy in International Perspective, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Women and Human Rights, Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Subseries II.2: Human Rights Internship Program (HRIP), 1991-1999
    - Internship Information Packets, 1991-1996, (3 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 4 to 6)
    - "HRIP: Domestic and Public Interest Fellowships/Grants," 1997 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - "HRIP: Foreign Summer Placements," 1997 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - "Internship Program Placement Packet," 1999 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Series III: Training and Capacity Building Programs, 1987-2004.
  - Subseries III.1: Human Rights Advocates Program (HRAP), 1989-2004
    - Administrative Files
      - Advocates Focus Session--Notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Program Description and Selection Criteria, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Background Information, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Funding--Open Society Proposal, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Action Plan, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Coordinator's Report, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Program Goals, 1994, 1999-2003, (5 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 7 to 11)
      - Administration Checklist, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Overview of Program Requirements, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Recruitment and Selection Timeline, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Participant Goals, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Advocates Advisory Board
      - Minutes and Notes, 1995-1999, (9 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 16 to 24)
      - McLaughlin Report on Program Evaluation, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Planning and Development Notes, 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence with Board Members
        - Blyberg, Ann, 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Dias, Clarence, 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 4)
        - Dimenstein, Gilberto, 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 5)
        - Henriques, Zelma, 1989-1999 (Box 9, Folder 6)
        - Jones, Sydney, 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 7)
        - Posner, Michael, 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 8)
        - Sandosham, Surita, 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 9)
        - Shapiro, Steve, 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Application Procedures, 1994-2003 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1998, (4 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 12 to 15)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1997 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1999-2002 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Courses
      - Data Analysis and Presentation, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Report Writing for Human Rights, 1995-1997, (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Electronic Files, 1994-1999 (Box 26)
      - Notes, 1994-1999 (3.5" floppy disks) (46 disks) (Box 26)
      - Untitled, undated (51/4" floppy disk) (Box 26)
    - Evaluations (Box 10)
      - Alumni Evaluations, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Board Evaluations, 1994-1996 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Faculty Evaluations, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Evaluation by Jack McLaughlin, CU Policy Analyst, 1996 March (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Ford Foundation Evaluations, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - External Evaluation, 2001, (3 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 11 to 13)
      - Advocates Evaluations
        - 1989 (Box 11, Folder 1)
        - 1990, (2 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 2 to 3)
        - 1991 (Box 11, Folder 4)
        - 1992 (Box 11, Folder 5)
        - 1993 (Box 11, Folder 6)
        - 1994, (3 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 7 to 9)
        - 1995, (3 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 10 to 12)
        - 1996 (Box 11, Folder 13)
        - 1996 (Box 12, Folder 1)
        - 1997, (2 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 2 to 3)
        - 1998, (2 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 4 to 5)
        - 1999 (Box 12, Folder 6)
        - 2000, (3 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 7 to 9)
        - 2001, (2 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 10 to 11)
        - 2002 (Box 13, Folder 1)
        - 2003, (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Internships, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Newsletters--Advocate, 1995-1999 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Orientation
      - Prearrival Packets, 1994-1999 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Information Packets and Schedules, 1989-2000, (3 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 7 to 8)
      - Information Packets and Schedules, 2001-2004, (2 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Press Releases, 1998-2000 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Receptions
      - Farewell and Welcome, 1994-1999 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Wang Juntao and Xido Tian, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Reports
      - Progress Report, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - 10th Anniversary Review--Brochure, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - Annual Reports, 1990-1991 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - Annual Reports, 2000-2001, (3 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 9 to 11)
    - Roundtables and Seminars
      - Brown Bag Series--Flyers and Handouts, 1991-199, (3 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 12 to 14)
      - Oversees Aid and Third World Human Rights Organizations--Conference Proposal (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Training Skills Workshop Schedule, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - A Draft Handbook on Fact Finding and Documentation of Human Rights Violations, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence with Speakers, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - "Promoting and Protecting Human Rights through the United Nations" by Stephen Marks--Lecture to Advocates, 1997 February 20 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - "Promoting and Protecting Human Rights in the United Nations System" by Stephen Marks--Lecture to Advocates, 1998 February 11 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Human Rights Challenges for the 21st Century--Roundtable Packet, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - Advocates Program Workshop--Packet, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Seminar with Reebock Human Rights Award Winners, 1998-1999, (2 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 9 to 10)
      - Public Presentations by Advocates--Flyers, 1998-2003 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Roundtables--Questions, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Schedules
      - Weekly Schedules, undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - Program Schedule, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - Program Schedules, 1994-1995, (3 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 15 to 17)
      - Program Schedules, 1998-1999, (2 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 18 to 19)
      - Seminar Schedule, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Visits
      - Department Visits, 1994-1998, (4 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 2 to 5)
      - NGO Visits, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Washington DC Trip, 1995-2003 (3 visits) (Box 16, Folder 7 to 9)
    - Websites
      - Advocate Network Website, 2001, (2 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 10 to 11)
      - Reebock RAWnet Proposal, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Subseries III.2: Belldegrun Human Rights Research and Training Fellowship at CSHR, 1997-2002
    - Program Brochures, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - "Corporate Ethics and Human Rights: A Comparative Profile in Telecommunication Industry," by Leila Mustanoja, Belldegrun Fellow, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Evaluations, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Orientation, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Thanks to Scandinavia Foundation--Correspondence and Budget Information, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Subseries III.3: The Religion, Human Rights and Religious Freedom Program, 1994-1999
    - Administration--Program Description and Goals, 1995-1998 (two Folders) (Box 17, Folder 7 to 8)
    - Annual Conference
      - Human Rights Movements and Religious Organizations in Russia and Eastern Europe after 1985 1995 November 17, (2 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 9 to 10)
      - Religious Freedom and Human Rights: State and Church in Eastern Europe, 1996 March 25-26, (4 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 11 to 14)
      - Religious Organizations and Human Rights Movement: Affinities and Divergences, 1997 March 24-25, (5 Folders) (Box 17)
      - The Protection of Religious Minorities, Religious Freedom and Human Rights in Post Communist Europe, 1998 March 16-18 (Box 17, Folder 6 to 10)